Castañeda mss., 1950-1991 LMC 2719
Lilly Library
Castañeda mss.
1950-1991
Lilly Library
Castañeda, Hector-Neri, 1924-1991
LMC 2719
100 Boxes
The Castañeda mss., 1950-1991, consist of the papers, correspondence, and professional files of Indiana University Professor of Philosphy Hector-Neri Castañeda, 1924-1991.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Hector-Neri Castañeda, 1924-1991, was a noted Indiana University Professor of Philosphy. Born in Guatemala, he immigrated to the United States to study at University of Minnesota, where he recieved his B.A, M.A, and PhD in Philosophy. Before his professorial position at Indiana, he founded the philosophy journal Noûs while full-time faculty at Wayne State University. Castañeda recieved fellowships and grants for his work from the Guggenheim Foundation, the T. Andrew Mellon Foundation, the National Endowment for the Humanities, and the National Science Foundation. He was elected President of the American Philosophical Association Central Division in 1979, was named to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences in 1990, and received the Presidential Medal of Honor from the Government of Guatemala in 1991.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series: I. Correspondence, II. Subject Files, III. Noûs files, and IV. Writings
Scope and Content Note
Subject Files include faculty files, professional and personal papers related to philosophical method, N.E.H Seminars, topics A-Z, and philosophical topics. Noûs files includes files related to the Noûs publication. Writings include some re-prints.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1992
Indiana University; Castañeda, Hector-Neri, 1924-1991; Indiana University Faculty; Philosophy; Philosophy--Periodicals
- Correspondence, (20 boxes) (Box 1-20)
  Scope and Content Note:
  Series includes boxes 1-20.
  - Re: Human Action (Box 73)
  - Re: "Review of Metaphysics" (Box 73)
  - Re: "Reflections" (Box 73)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 76)
  - W. Lenzen (Box 86)
  - Center for Latin American & Caribbean Studies (Box 86)
  - Univ. of Guatemala (Box 86)
  - On Method, reviews, responses (Box 87)
  - Corresp. - A (Box 88)
  - THOUGHTS, Sellars-Castañeda corresp. (Box 90)
  - Scott M. Davidson (Box 94)
  - Christopher Macann (Box 94)
  - Madhabendranath Mitra, Truth (Box 94)
  - Michael Morgan, Platonic Piety (Box 94)
  - Georgia Green, Pragmatics (Box 94)
  - Renee Darosky (Box 94)
  - Kyburg Jr. Review (Box 94)
  - Taylor, Charles, Source of Self (Box 94)
  - Various Reviewers (Box 95)
  - various personal (Box 97)
  - Kant's philosophies (Box 97)
- Subject Files (Box 21)
  - Faculty Files
    - Erasmus Anthology, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Erasmus Anthology (Box 21)
    - Conferences, 1990 (Box 21)
    - San Marino Conference, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Mexico, 1990 (Box 21)
    - lectures, 1989 (Box 21)
    - Rotterdam (Box 21)
    - Simposio latino-Amer, 1987 (Box 21)
    - Russian philosophy (Box 21)
    - Self and identity (Box 21)
    - conferences, 1989 (Box 21)
    - Europe, 1989 (Box 21)
    - Pierce Congress, 1989 (Box 21)
    - Luesden colloquium (Box 21)
    - Heidelberg, 1989 (Box 21)
    - Papers to write (Box 21)
    - Freiburg symposium, January 1986 (Box 21)
    - Freiburg symposium (Box 21)
    - Freiburg, Fall, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Freiburg symposium proceedings (Box 21)
    - Hegel Kongress, 1987 (Box 21)
    - Wittenstein symposium (Box 21)
    - congresses, 1987 (Box 21)
    - Germany, 1987 (Box 21)
    - APA - Los Angeles, 1986 (Box 21)
    - Stanford, 1984 (Box 21)
    - Amsterdam & Venice, 1985 (Box 21)
    - Logic, informatics and law (Box 21)
    - Houston Law Conference (Box 21)
    - Philosophy of law (Box 21)
    - 4th interamerican congress, 1977; (3 folders) (Box 21)
    - Febbraio, 1974 (Box 21)
    - Centro Febbraio, 1974 (Box 21)
    - German semiotic society (Box 21)
    - Trento conference (Box 21)
    - California trip, 1979 (Box 21)
    - 16th international congress, 1978 (Box 21)
    - Guatemala honor, 1991 (Box 21)
    - Conference on indexical reference (Box 21)
    - Indexicality & history of philosophy (Box 21)
    - papers, 1991 (Box 21)
    - ICUS 5th, 9th... (Box 22)
    - International Conference on the Unity of Science (Box 22)
    - Leibnitz a Paris...conference, 1976 (Box 22)
    - Winnipeg conference on action, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Bielefeld symposium papers, 1975 (Box 22)
    - VIII interamerican conference (Box 22)
    - APA meetings, 1974 (Box 22)
    - APA - Western Division program, 1974 (Box 22)
    - APA Meetings, 1965 (Box 22)
    - Wayne student papers, 1965-1966 (Box 22)
    - University of Texas colloquia, 1965-1966 (Box 22)
      Scope and Contents
      empty folder
    - Wayne colloquia, 2 Folders (Box 22)
    - Symposium, 1966 (Box 22)
    - Cincinatti symposium -, Nov. 1966 (Box 22)
    - University of W. Ontario colloquium -, Nov. 1966 (Box 22)
    - Academie du Midi Inst. fur Philosophie (Box 22)
    - Amintaphil (Box 22)
    - Semiotics and the humanities (Box 22)
    - lectures, 1988 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence (pending) (Box 22)
    - lectures (Box 22)
    - Papers to write (Box 22)
    - IU Comparative Literature (Box 22)
    - Dictator (Box 22)
    - Computer - Changes (Box 22)
    - IU Institue for Advanced Studies (Box 22)
    - Cognitive Studies Institute (Box 22)
    - Hegel - Vereinigung (Box 22)
    - Honors Program (Box 22)
    - International admission forms (Box 22)
    - Latin American seminar (Box 22)
    - Latin American studies (Box 22)
    - Library (Box 22)
    - Library School (Box 22)
    - IU Lingusitics club (Box 22)
    - Leibnitz Society (Box 22)
    - IU Press (Box 22)
      Contains folder on Bibliotheca philosphica
    - IU Spanish and Portugese (Box 22)
    - Poynter Center (Box 22)
    - Action needed today (Box 22)
    - Philopsophy of Law International Association (Box 22)
    - Society for Exact Philosophy, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Southern Society for Philosophy and Psychology (Box 23)
    - Sociedad interamericana de filosofia (Box 23)
    - The Aristotelian Society (Box 23)
    - US Institute of Peace (Box 23)
    - Professor World Peace Academy (Box 23)
    - American Philosophical Association, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - APA Presidential Address (Box 23)
    - [APA Western Division presidential address], (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Metaphysics Society of America (Box 23)
    - Western Division, 1977-1978; (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Western Division: presidency, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - [Castañeda blue notebook] (Box 23)
    - APA Committee on International Cooperation (Box 23)
    - Indiana Philosophical Association (Box 23)
    - Sociedad Venezolana de Filosofia (Box 23)
    - Canadian Philosophical Association (Box 23)
    - Philosophical Association (Box 23)
    - The American Society for Vaule Inquiry (Box 23)
    - Sociedad Argentina de Analysis filosofico (Box 23)
    - Ethical theories (Box 24)
    - Ethics: Questions (Box 24)
    - Problems in ethics (Box 24)
    - Ethical theories, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - Ethical theories: subjectivism (Box 24)
    - Ethics: notes (Box 24)
    - Ethics: exams (Box 24)
    - Duke University (Box 24)
    - Ethics: notes on utilitarianism (Box 24)
    - Ethics [classes] (Box 24)
    - Ethics 342 (Box 24)
    - P344: Ethical theories (Box 24)
    - P140-Ethics, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - Ethics: grounds of obligation (Box 24)
    - Moral relativism (Box 24)
    - Exams introduction (Box 24)
    - Ethics, problems and questions (Box 24)
    - Class materials (Box 24)
    - General material: introduction (Box 24)
    - Introduction reading: Locke (Box 24)
    - Malcom's arguments against computers and trees (Box 24)
    - Philosophy of the mind (Box 24)
    - Adult education puzzles (Box 24)
    - [Department of Philosophy course descriptions] (Box 24)
    - Model logic problems (Box 24)
    - Deduction - PC (Box 24)
    - Rules for Venn diagrams (Box 24)
    - Pro-validity (Box 24)
    - Tautologies (Box 24)
    - P150 - Spring 83 (Box 24)
    - Logic - exercise No. 5 fun (Box 25)
    - Definitions (Box 25)
    - Logic P105 Summ. 83 (Box 25)
    - Logic P150 syllabus exercises, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Logic of imperatives (Box 25)
    - Russell paradox (Box 25)
    - PC - symbolization (Box 25)
    - Problems in omnipotence (Box 25)
    - General problems or puzzles (Box 25)
    - Exercise #6 - puzzles (Box 25)
    - Problems (Box 25)
    - Problems in propositional calculus (Box 25)
    - PC Problems (Box 25)
    - Logic exercises (Box 25)
    - Logic 150 (Box 25)
    - English connectives (Box 25)
    - Propositional Calculus (Box 25)
      (empty folder)
    - Substitution (Box 25)
    - Identity p.1 (Box 25)
    - Logic exam 1 (Box 25)
    - Logic exams (Box 25)
    - Logic exams #2, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Logic exams #3 (Box 25)
    - Final Exams: logic (Box 25)
    - Honors logic (Box 25)
    - General material: logic (Box 25)
    - Logical propositions (Box 25)
    - Symbolic Logic (Box 25)
    - Logic - quiz #3 (Box 25)
    - Logical systems 1 (Box 25)
    - Fallacies, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Syllogisms (Box 26)
    - P150 - Venn diagrams prop. calc. problems (Box 26)
    - Philosophy of science, (2 folders) (Box 26)
    - Greek Philosophy (Box 26)
    - Russell: universals (Box 26)
    - Universals: questions (Box 26)
    - Kant: tests (Box 26)
    - [HNC resumes] (Box 26)
    - loose papers, (14 folders) (Box 26)
    - Human action (Box 27)
    - Humanities (Box 27)
    - CIC (Box 27)
    - LA office review (Box 27)
    - LA advisory committee to the dean (Box 27)
    - Segal, Judith (Box 27)
    - Psotska, Joseph (Box 27)
    - Philosophy Pilot courses (Box 27)
    - [P105], (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - P105, 1979-1980 (Box 27)
    - Basic skills, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Basic skills, 1980-1981 (Box 27)
    - Basic skills, 1981-1982 (Box 27)
    - Indiana University, (3 folders) (Box 27)
    - Comm. on institutional cooperation (Box 27)
    - Latino affairs: budget (Box 27)
    - Latino affairs deanship: budget, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Latino affairs I, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Latino affairs: plans (Box 27)
    - Latino affairs: deanship (Box 27)
    - Student meetings (Box 27)
    - Latino fellowships (Box 27)
    - Latino affairs information, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - [env. of materials from Russell Salmon] (Box 28)
    - LA Review, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Latino student survey (Box 28)
    - [no label - with a folder marked P105] (Box 28)
    - Groups, 1981-1982 (Box 28)
    - [no label - basic skills coordinating committee?] (Box 28)
    - [no label - basic skills?] (Box 28)
    - Gros Louis, Ken (Box 28)
    - Neal, Homer (Box 28)
    - Schapp, Ward (Box 28)
    - Teaching (Box 28)
    - Freshman seminars (Box 28)
    - Insurance and retire (Box 28)
    - Uncertainty seminar, 1982 (Box 28)
    - Applied ethics (Box 28)
    - Social data (Box 28)
    - IU Alumni (association) (Box 28)
    - Oscar Ewing professorship (Box 28)
    - Department publicity committee (Box 28)
    - Doctoral dissertations (current) (Box 28)
    - Students letters (Box 28)
    - IU Credit Union (Box 28)
    - Universities: student problems (Box 28)
    - Department - job placement (Box 28)
    - Graduate students (Box 28)
    - Professors union (Box 28)
    - IU Philosophy Department salaries (Box 28)
    - Wages and salaries (Box 28)
    - Library (Box 28)
    - Phil. Dept. Info. (Box 28)
    - Department (Box 28)
    - IU Philosophy Department meetings (Box 28)
    - IU Philosophy Department, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Ethics Qualification exams (Box 29)
    - IU: Preliminary examinations, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Personnel committee (Box 29)
    - Philosophy Department - my memos (Box 29)
    - ethics certification, 1990 (Box 29)
    - IU Philosophy Dept. course offering (Box 29)
    - Visiting scholars (Box 29)
    - Graduate School (Box 29)
    - Research incentive program (Box 29)
    - University: some reflexions (Box 29)
    - University relations (Box 29)
    - Indiana University, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Spring, 1990 (Box 29)
    - Ethics 540, 1988 (Box 29)
    - Philosophy of language S, 1988 (Box 29)
    - P541, 1987 (Box 29)
    - P542 Theory of action, 1987 (Box 29)
    - Leibniz, 1986 (Box 29)
    - Fall ethical theories, 1984 (Box 29)
    - [Student papers & comments on] (Box 29)
    - [P150 summer 83] (Box 29)
    - P520 (83) (Box 29)
    - Ethical theories (Box 29)
    - Human action (Box 29)
    - Human action - Maracaibo (Box 29)
    - Ethical theories:, 1980 (Box 29)
    - Metaphysic: Reference, Fall, 1978 (Box 29)
    - Ethical theories, S78 (Box 29)
    - Kant, 1975 (Box 29)
    - Ethical theories Spring, 1974 (Box 29)
    - Leibnitz, 1973 (Box 30)
    - Epistemology, Fall, 1972 (Box 30)
    - Ethics, Spring, 1972 (Box 30)
    - Seminar: indicators, quasi-indicators, names, etc. (Box 30)
    - Ethics seminar, Summer, 1971 (Box 30)
    - University of Pittsburgh - Winter, 1972 (Box 30)
    - Seminars, graduate work (Box 30)
    - University of Cincinatti: Fall, 1970 (Box 30)
    - University of Western Ontario: Fall, 1968 (Box 30)
    - Ethics seminar: Fall, 1969 (Box 30)
    - Students evaluation (Box 30)
    - Class statements (Box 30)
    - [no labels], (8 folders) (Box 30)
    - Perception II (Box 30)
    - Papers to be read II - personal, (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - [no labels], (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - Papers to be read - for personal enlightenment (Box 30)
    - Bibliographies (Box 30)
    - Knowledge and belief: bibliography (Box 30)
    - Propositions: bibliography (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 73)
    - P366 (Box 73)
    - Houston Law & Tech Conference, 1985 (Box 74)
    - "Intentions" (Box 74)
    - On Feldman (Box 74)
    - On Feldman & Goble (Box 74)
    - Heidelberg Seminar (Box 74)
    - International symposium, April 1983 (Box 74)
    - Philosophy of Language, P520 (Box 74)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 75)
    - Misc. faculty writings, (3 folders) (Box 75)
    - Dr. M Spitzer writings, drafts (Box 75)
    - notes, miscellaneous (Box 75)
    - Philosophy class proposal, 1987 (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 75)
    - Latino Affairs annual report (Box 75)
    - Latino Affairs, complaints to V.P., 1979-1981 (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box 76)
    - Latino Affairs grants & funding (Box 76)
    - Miscellaneous faculty writings, f.4 (Box 76)
    - Rotterdam, Germany (Box 76)
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 76)
    - Faculty files, (3 folders) (Box 76)
    - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 77)
    - Uncertainty Seminar, (2 folders) (Box 77)
    - Miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box 77)
    - Philosophy Course exercises, (4 folders) (Box 78)
    - Revista Nacional de Cultura, 1956 (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 78)
    - Entailment, books 2 & 3 (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 79)
    - Elección, Constitución y Democracia (Box 81)
    - Study (Box 81)
    - Study: notes (Box 81)
    - Reply to Perry. draft (Box 81)
    - Lectures & meetings, 1991 (Box 81)
    - Brain letter (Spanish) (Box 81)
    - Miscellaneous, (7 folders) (Box 81)
    - Thinking and Logic: papers (Box 81)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 81)
    - Concentration exercises (Box 82)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 82)
    - Ernesto Sota (Box 82)
    - book publishing (Box 82)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 82)
    - notes, Logic (Box 82)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 82)
    - Logic exercises, (2 folders) (Box 82)
    - Bruck dissertation copy (Box 82)
    - Logic notes & exercises (Box 82)
    - Adult Education (Box 82)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 82)
    - Logic notes (H.N.C.) (Box 82)
    - Logic notes & exercises, (3 folders) (Box 82)
    - Lecciones de Lógica, originales revisados (Box 82)
    - P150 Spring, 1983 (Box 83)
    - M. Dunn's syllabi & notes (Box 83)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 83)
    - "He," final version (Box 84)
    - Comments on Taylor's "Mechanism & Purpose" (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box 84)
    - R. McArthur's Writings (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 85)
    - PROFILES (Box 85)
    - Autobiography (Box 85)
    - PROFILES, Autobiography (Box 85)
    - Latino Affairs (Box 85)
    - APA; West Division -, 1966 (Box 85)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 85)
    - cuaderno de trabajo (Box 85)
    - Ruth Millikan (Box 86)
    - Coffa A. (Box 86)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 86)
    - D. Glidden (Box 86)
    - Martin Dako (Box 86)
    - Nathan Salmon (Box 86)
    - Manfred Frank, eur. (Box 86)
    - Rotterdam Lectures (Box 86)
    - Eco's Quine's Congress (Box 86)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 86)
    - Leibniz (Box 86)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 86)
    - P150 Elemental Logic (Box 86)
    - Philosophy Department (Box 86)
    - P522 Leibniz, Spring, 1986 (Box 86)
    - Thinking, Language & exp., Reviews & comments (Box 86)
    - P366 Philosophy of Action, 1977 (Box 86)
    - P541, (1987) (Box 86)
    - P540 Ethics (Box 86)
    - P140 Ethical Theories, Fall, '82 (Box 86)
    - Separatas (Box 86)
    - North American Kant Society (Box 86)
    - Int'l Philosophy of Law & Social Phil. (Box 86)
    - Publications: Stanford (Box 86)
    - American Academy of Arts & Sciences (Box 86)
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 86)
    - HNC (Box 87)
    - U. of Minn. Anthology (Box 87)
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 87)
    - C.I. Lewis Symposium (Box 88)
    - Latin Am. Working Papers (Box 88)
    - Frege Symposium (Box 88)
    - conferences & colloquia, 1970 (Box 88)
    - Wadsworth Publishing Co. (Box 88)
    - Abraxas (Box 88)
    - Works in Progress (Box 88)
    - Publishing possibilities (Box 88)
    - CV, Suppl. Payroll voucher, fac. summary report (Box 88)
    - Hector-Neri Castañeda, (4 folders) (Box 88)
    - Western Division - General (Box 88)
    - Western Division: meetings, 1977 (Box 88)
    - Western Division: meetings, 1976 (Box 88)
    - A.P.A Western Division: meetings, 1975 (Box 88)
    - A.P.A Western Division: meetings, 1974 (Box 88)
    - A.P.A Western Division: meetings, 1973 (Box 88)
    - A.P.A Western Division: meetings, 1972 (Box 88)
    - A.P.A Western Division: symposia, 1971 (Box 88)
    - Oberlin Colloquium, 1974 (Box 89)
    - P140 Elementary Ethics (Box 89)
    - Genser (Box 89)
    - Ethics: seminar (Box 89)
    - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 89)
    - Sellars - Reprints (Box 90)
    - P150 (Box 91)
    - P540 Ethics (Box 91)
    - Faculty report, 1987 (Box 91)
    - Faculty reports (Box 91)
    - Plato (Box 91)
    - [loose papers put into 3 folders], (3 folders) (Box 91)
    - Miscellaneous, (11 folders) (Box 92)
    - Sellars (Box 93)
    - Ethics Paper (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 93)
    - from Samuel M. Woolsey, Jr. (Box 93)
    - Hintikka on Analyticity (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous student notes (Box 93)
    - "The Private Language Problem" (Box 93)
    - "Private Language" and replies (Box 93)
    - Private Language (Box 93)
    - Private Lang. Problem (Box 93)
    - Ed's Papers (Box 93)
    - Nakhnikan, "Prescriptive Assertions" (Box 93)
    - Lehrer on "I Can" (Box 93)
    - Philosophy of Mind (Box 93)
    - For Haller (Box 94)
    - Garda Olas (Box 94)
    - Spizer - Is, egos... (Box 94)
    - Events and Causation (Box 94)
    - Golly Gosh puzzle (Box 94)
    - Miscellaneous, (11 folders) (Box 95)
    - notes for lecture on "He" (Box 96)
    - Scopes (Box 96)
    - Sellars (Box 96)
    - Intro to Philosophy (Box 96)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 96)
    - Etico Lecturas (Box 96)
    - Etico "Hutchinson" (Box 96)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 96)
    - Dissertation Richard Sharvy (Box 96)
    - Logic III, (2 folders) (Box 96)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 96)
    - Logic Exercises (Box 96)
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 97)
    - Metaphilosophy lectures (Box 97)
    - Philosophy as a worldview (Box 97)
    - Knowledge (Chisolm symp.) (Box 97)
    - Pensamiento y la structura del mundo (Box 97)
    - Hist. Phil. & PAIC (Box 97)
    - Leibniz Complete Prop. Logic (Box 97)
    - Almog - Schiffer (Box 97)
    - Latino Newsletter, files (Box 99)
    - Admin. Portfolio (Box 99)
    - L. American research guides (Box 99)
    - P 105 Materials (Box 99)
    - F, 1980 (Box 99)
    - Basic Skills, 1979 (Box 99)
    - F, 1979 (Box 99)
    - Class Files, misc. (Box 99)
    - Groups Programs, sponsoring grants (Box 99)
    - Miscellaneous class files (Box 99)
    - Miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box 99)
    - P 105 Class materials, 1980 (Box 99)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 100)
    - Minn. Anthology, (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - Elementary Logic (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 100)
  - Philosophical topics (Box 90)
    - Purpose, Action & Ought: integrated theory of action (Box 90)
    - Quantification (Box 90)
    - Self-knowledge (Box 90)
    - Theories, scientific (Box 90)
    - Universals (Box 90)
    - Utility: theory of (Box 90)
    - Utilitarianism - discussions (Box 90)
    - Ethics & Logic (Box 92)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 92)
    - Kraft (Box 93)
    - truth in ethics (Box 93)
    - Imperatives, Decisions, and Rules, Ends (Box 93)
    - Attributions of self knowledge (Box 96)
    - Imperatives, Decisions & Oughts, (2 folders) (Box 96)
    - Mult. Faces Knowing (Box 97)
    - Objects, Existence & Guise Theory (Box 97)
    - Sprache und Erfahrung, (2 folders) (Box 97)
    - Entailment (Box 98)
    - Existence (Box 98)
    - Frege (Box 98)
    - Geometry: Frege (Box 98)
    - Good reasons approach (Box 98)
    - Hedonism (Box 98)
    - Hintikka on knowledge and belief (Box 98)
    - J. Hintikka articles (Box 98)
    - identity (Box 98)
    - Imperatives: logic of (Box 98)
    - Hypothetical imperatives (Box 98)
    - Self (Box 98)
    - Style (Box 98)
    - Thinking and world (Box 98)
    - Belief of the structure of the world (Box 98)
    - Critica (Box 98)
    - Individualism and non-identity (Box 98)
    - Ethics (Box 98)
    - Meetings, 1967 (Box 98)
    - Meetings, 1968 (Box 98)
    - Meetings - papers, 1969 (Box 98)
    - NOUS referred (Box 98)
    - W.V.O Quine (Box 98)
    - Knowing that one knows (Box 98)
    - Knowledge: of other minds, (2 folders) (Box 98)
    - Knowledge: of self (Box 98)
    - Acts, the knowledge of obligation... (Box 98)
    - Ought, value, and utilitariansim (reprints) (Box 98)
    - Semantics of ought-to-do (Box 98)
    - Kaplan - Logic of Demonstratives (Box 100)
  - Philosopical Method (Box 31)
    - Utilitarianism: bibliography (Box 31)
    - Actions, causation - bibliography (Box 31)
    - Ethics textbook (Box 31)
    - Agent, language... (Box 31)
    - [no label] (Box 31)
    - Thinking and the structure of the world - comments, 2 Folders (Box 31)
    - [no label], 3 Folders (Box 31)
    - C: Action, perception (Box 31)
    - C: Structure of mortality, 2 Folders (Box 31)
    - Intentionality, minds, & perception (Box 31)
    - Morality and language of conduct (Box 31)
    - Reviews JSL, 1961 (Box 31)
    - Plato on relations - new comments (Box 31)
    - Plato's main Phaedo theory of relations, forms, and particulars (Box 31)
    - Suhrkamp verlag (Box 31)
    - TLE comments (Box 31)
    - Thinking, language & experience (corres.) (Box 31)
    - On philosophical method (Box 31)
    - H-N.: German anthology (Box 31)
    - Meaning and cognition (Box 31)
      contains folder: McPherran
    - Logic - connectives (Box 31)
    - Methods & self - McIntyre, Richards, Tomberlin (Box 31)
    - Guise theory (Box 31)
    - Braini (Box 31)
    - Familia (Box 31)
    - Class statements (Box 32)
    - Reference (Box 32)
    - Problems of Ontology (Box 32)
    - Research lecture, 2 Folders (Box 32)
    - Guide theory (Box 32)
    - Bello symposium (Box 32)
    - Tenses (Box 32)
    - Castañeda profile (Box 32)
    - Profiles: H-NC, (4 folders) (Box 32)